The system wanted them to become soldiers. One soldier just wanted to be human.
Tigerland is a drama, war film directed by Joel Schumacher.
A group of recruits go through Advanced Infantry Training at Fort Polk, Louisiana's infamous
Tigerland, last stop before Vietnam for tens of thousands of young men in 1971.
Pvt. Roland Bozz, played by Colin Farrell.
Pvt. Jim Paxton, played by Matthew Davis.
Pvt. Miter, played by Clifton Collins Jr..
Pvt. Cantwell, played by Tom Guiry.
Pvt. Wilson, played by Shea Whigham.
Staff Sgt. Thomas, played by James MacDonald.
Tigerland is a 2000 American war drama film directed by
Joel Schumacher and starring Colin Farrell.
It takes place in a training camp for soldiers to be sent to the Vietnam War.
The film premiered at the 2000 Toronto International Film Festival in September
2000 before being released by 20th Century Fox on October 6, 2000.
Despite receiving generally positive reviews for its story, direction, Farrell's performance, screenplay, and emotional
weight, the film was a box-office bomb, grossing only $148,701 worldwide against a $10 million budget.
It was one of Schumacher's best reviewed films in his filmography.
The film explores themes of 1970s, louisiana, kansas, usa, guitar player, awol.
The tone is emotional.